本字幕由 YYeTs人人影视 原创翻译制作
仅供学习 禁止用于任何商业盈利行为
更多影视更新 请登陆 www.YYeTs.com
■
翻译：Ｊ小糯    Soomii    红豆包    Iz
校对：Ｊ小糯      时间轴：grace
■
后期：鱼骨头      总监：stephanie
《开心汉堡店》
第一季第四集
蒂娜  你要是想在地上躺着
Tina, if you're gonna lay on the floor,
就来回滚一滚  省得等会我还得擦
at least roll around so I don't have to mop up later.
蒂娜发什么神经啊
What's wrong with Tina?
青春期嘛
Puberty.
没错  她正值青春萌动期
Yeah. She's pubing out right now pretty bad.
乔丹・斯德曼搬走了
Jordan Sturman moved away,
一种足球和棒球结合的游戏
我再也不能和他玩足棒球了
and now I'll never play kickball with him again.
-你赶紧自杀吧  -没错
- Oh, you should kill yourself. - Yeah!
吉恩  露易丝  别使坏
Gene and Louise, be nice.
你们俩也要经历青春期的
You're gonna go through adolescence, too, you know.
那个德行的吗  真恶心
Like that? Oh, sick!
-她会传染给我们吗  -老妈你快闭嘴
- Is she contagious? - You shut up, mom!
你们自己看
Watch it.
你伤害不了我  我已经死了
You can't hurt me. I'm already dead.
你那小胡子能给我吗
Can I have your mustache, then?
这只是一根毛
It's only one hair.
好事的开端
It's the beginning of a great thing.
好长一根毛
It's a huge hair.
我不能把它剃了
I can't cut it.
这样很好看呀  别烦她了
It's beautiful. Leave her alone.
-蒂娜  你很美  -我来把它拔出来
- You're beautiful, Tina. - Let me pull it out.
让我踩在你胸上
Let me put my foot on your chest.
吉恩  快下去  别瞎闹了
Gene, get off. Enough.
走吧  吉恩  我们去好好享受一下童年
Come on, Gene. Let's go have a childhood.
半个小时后
我的心哟  我的心哎
My heart. My heart.
宝贝  别吵  我打电话呢
Shh, sweetie. I'm on the phone.
金泽郁闷着呢  继续继续  金泽
Ginger is very upset. Ha ha! Go on, Ginger.
什么  不是吧
What? Ha ha ha! No!
行了  蒂娜  快起来  你来烤肉
Come on, Tina, get up. You're on the grill.
为什么
Why?
好了  打起精神来  这个很好玩的
Come on. Cheer up, you know? We're having fun.
-好玩吗  -当然了
- We are? - Yeah.
还有  这是父女互动时间哦
Plus, it's father-daughter time.
为什么吉恩和露易丝不必像我这样玩耍呢
Why don't Gene and Louise have to have fun like this?
蒂娜  你是长女
Well, Tina, you're the oldest,
你肩负汉堡店重任
and you have added responsibilities here,
比如  星期六的早晨  你要烤肉
like on Saturday mornings, for example, you're on the grill.
他们烤我不放心
I can't trust them on the grill.
火会从烤架下窜出来  你知道的
You know that. Fire comes out of it.
我知道  讨厌死了
Ha ha! I know. It's awful.
好了  再见
All right. Bye.
金泽的猫死了  死得很滑稽
Ginger's cat died, but in a really funny way.
蒂娜  我们刚刚看见史上最不可思议的事
Tina, we just saw the most amazing thing ever.
这将是我人生中最美好的一天
This might be the best day of my life,
除了你们俩出生的那天
besides the day you kids were born.
难以用言语解释
Words can't explain this.
你必须亲眼看看
You just have to see it.
快跟我们走  来嘛  蒂娜
Come with us. Come on, Tina!
我不能去
I can't.
老爸是不会让我离开工作岗位的
Dad won't let me leave work.
我是说  玩耍岗位
I mean, fun.
他是不会让我在父女互动时间离开的
He won't let me leave fun father-daughter time.
你还津津乐道的
You fell for that?
这不是真的吧
That's not a real thing.
快跟我们走
Come with us.
鲍勃  你就让她走嘛
Aw, Bob, let her go.
好吧  成
All right, fine.
不过你会错过我刮掉烤架上糊肉的环节
But you're gonna miss when I scrape off the grill,
那是一天中最出彩的一个环节
that's the best part of the day,
虽然今天进行得很慢
although today has been pretty slow,
可能不会有那么多的糊肉
so there's not gonna be as much gunk to...
怎么都走了
Everyone is gone.
你俩不应该引导一下被蒙住眼睛的人吗
Aren't you supposed to lead someone who's blindfolded?
那样惊喜会被毁掉的
It would ruin the surprise.
我们要去哪
Where are we going?
起初我们还以为那是个霹雳舞蹈班
At first, we thought it was a breakdancing class,
为智力或身体残障者开设的班
而后我们觉得那是一个特殊需求班
and then we thought it was a special needs class.
现在我们觉得那是个特殊需求霹雳舞蹈班
Now we think it might be a special needs breakdancing class.
还有  它充满巴西风情
Also, it's Brazilian...
极其欢腾
Slash hilarious.
-听起来很有趣...  -很傻缺吗
- Sounds interest... - Stupid?
它可比你想象中的傻缺多了
Oh, it's even more stupid than you could possibly imagine.
到那之前你就等着吧
Just wait till we get near it.
他们把鞋全都脱了
They take off their shoes,
当门打开时
so when they open the door,
整间屋子都弥漫着一股脚丫子味
the whole block smells like feet.
在脚丫子味中熏陶的脚丫子
Feet that have been cooked in feet.
巴西战舞练功房
-好棒  -依旧很有趣
- Yes! - Still funny. Ha!
你能闻到吗
Oh! Ooh. Ooh. Can you smell that?
正是那股穿墙而透的气味
That's just what's coming through the walls.
闻起来很有异国情调啊
That smells exotic,
一股牧场调料味
like ranch dressing.
他好动人
Whoa, he's beautiful.
那是男人吗
That's a man?
你要去哪
Where are you going?
我要去报名参加这个班
I'm signing up for that class.
什么  为什么
What? Why?
别开门
Don't open the door!
那股气味会秒杀我们的
The smell will kill us all!
让我进去  放开我
Let me go. Let go of me.
-不要  -不要
- No! - No!
臭脚丫子味
Oh, the feet smell.
The feet smell.
等一下  她那是干嘛
Wait. What is it?
-这是巴西战舞  -巴西战什么
- It's Capoeira. - Capo-what?
蒂娜  你确定你想练这个吗
Tina, are you really sure you want to do this?
是的  老爸  你就等着瞧吧
Yes, dad. Wait till you see it.
杰罗迷死人了  我有张DVD
Jairo is amazing. I have a DVD.
顺便说一下  那张DVD要十四块九毛五
Oh, by the way, I need $14.95 for the DVD.
等一下  啥  杰罗是啥
Wait. What? What's Jairo?
我叫杰罗
Ola. My name is Jairo.
欢迎来到巴西战舞世界
Welcome to the world of Capoeira.
巴西战舞是最迷人的自卫形式
Capoeira is the most seductive form of self-defense.
它将平和  搏击  心肺锻炼
It combines peacefulness, fighting, and cardio
完美结合于一身
in perfect harmony.
巴西战舞  让人心跳不已
Capoeira is breathtaking,
同时  让您保持心跳
but it is also breath-giving.
你可以通过赢取不同颜色的腰带晋级
You can advance through the stages by earning different colored cords
晋级赛名为  卓卡・德・考多艾斯
at the Troca de Cordoes.
我还以为你做的动作不对
Wow, I thought maybe you were doing it wrong,
但实际上看起来就是那个样子
but that's actually what it looks like.
他们又在敲铃鼓了
They're bringing the tambourine back.
那叫潘黛罗[葡语]  是巴西手鼓
That's a pandeiro, a Brazilian frame drum.
就是铃鼓嘛
It's a tambourine.
我去把我的拿来
I'm gonna get mine.
那些家伙根本不懂怎么演奏
Those guys don't know how to shake it.
我不懂  我在这里看的到底是什么
I don't get it. I mean, what am I looking at here?
这是什么  看着像某种舞蹈  是什么啊
What is it? Is it some kind of dancing. What is it?
杰罗说这不是舞蹈
Jairo says it's not dancing.
是街战的一种致命类型
It's a deadly form of street fighting.
是么
Oh, yeah?
用不着什么男老师来教你打斗的招数
Well, you don't need some male model to teach you how to fight.
老爸就是干这个的
That's what dads are for.
来  我来教你几招
Come on. I'll show you some stuff.
来跟你老爸打几拳
Box with your old man, huh?
很上道
There you go.
只要...   就这样
Just got to... there it is. Uh!
蒂娜  打得好  打得很好
Whoa, Tina. Good fight. Good fight.
看起来很欢乐
That was fun to watch.
杰罗说  如果我有学巴西战舞的天分
Jairo says if there's any Capoeira inside me,
上几节课他就能知道
he'll find it with enough classes.
杰罗生活经验丰富
Jairo knows a lot about life.
八节课后
杰罗说他会对动物催眠
Jairo says he can hypnotize animals.
但只有当它们愿意的时候才可以
But only if they want to be hypnotized...
蒂娜  别吵吵别吵吵
Tina, shh shh shh shh.
-他们经常被催眠  -蒂娜
- which they almost always do. - Tina!
杰罗说牙膏会损害牙齿
Jairo says toothpaste insults your teeth.
蒂娜  快去睡觉
Tina, go to bed.
杰罗每晚只需睡两个小时
Jairo only needs two hours of sleep a night
因为他控制着他的心脏
because he regulates his heart.
蒂娜  出去
Tina, get out.
-杰罗睁着眼睛睡觉  -蒂娜
- Jairo sleeps with his eyes open... - Tina!
好了  跟着我做
Okay. Just follow my lead.
巴西魂  巴西魂
Brazil! Brazil!
下课了
Class is over.
现在  我们有一个小时的开放练习时间
We now have an hour of open practice time,
完全是自愿参加的
which is completely optional
除非你对巴西战舞抱持认真的态度
unless you're serious about Capoeira.
我肯定要留下
Oh, I'm definitely staying.
蒂娜本应该在这儿烤肉的
Tina is supposed to be here to cover the grill.
都四点半多了
It's after 4:30.
她在上呆瓜课呢
She's at a kookaburra class.
老爸  烤架又着火了
Dad, the grill is doing that thing again.
怎么老出问题呢
What is your problem with fire?
你知道吗  走开  快走开
You know what? Go. Go away.
出去把垃圾收了  然后扔到垃圾箱里去
Go down and collect trash and bring it to the dumpster.
必须在店里收垃圾吗  还是去哪收都可以
Does it have to be from around here, or can we go anywhere?
-走开就是了  -好耶  收垃圾喽
- Just go. - Yeah! Trash!
垃圾  垃圾  垃圾  垃圾
Trash! Trash! Trash! Trash!
我昨天发现一条项链
Yesterday I found a necklace.
午间会议时间到了
It's time for my afternoon meeting,
在卫生间开的那个  你懂的
you know, in the bathroom.
四点半会议吗
Your 4:30 meeting?
没错  四点半会议
Yeah, my 4:30.
-那就去呗  -不行
- So go. - No.
蒂娜答应我到时间她会来的
Tina made a commitment to be here at a certain time.
我要下去提醒她一下
I'm going down there to remind her
-这里有事需要她做  -等等
- that she has a job here. - Wait.
那你的会议怎么办
What about your meeting?
我决定推迟今天的会议
Well, I'm postponing it today.
鲍勃  你不能这样
Bob, you can't do that.
就定在今晚十点半好了
I'm gonna set a time for 10:30 tonight.
鲍勃  我要告诉你的是
This is why I tell you, Bob,
把那个大会分成几个小会
just have little meetings throughout the day
在全天不同时段召开  每次拉一点
instead of one big one, little poops.
可熏死我了
Oof! Oh! That is horrible.
赶紧洗洗脚
Wash your feet.
我的脚感染了
I have an infection.
蒂娜  蒂蒂
Tina. Tine. Psst psst psst.
老爸  你来这里干什么
Dad, what are you doing here?
蒂娜  你该回去工作了
You're supposed to be back at work, Tina,
接替我一下  我要去开四点半会议呢
to cover me for my 4:30 meeting.
-老爸  -你好啊
- Dad... - Oh, hello.
请您拖鞋
Please remove your shoes.
我可不想脱鞋
Oh, I don't want to take off my shoes.
我只是来接我的女儿蒂娜的
I'm just picking up my daughter Tina.
你是蒂娜的爸爸啊
Oh, you are Tina's father.
我叫杰罗  寓意是"旋转大师"
Ola. My name is Jairo, like "Gyrate."
我叫鲍勃
Ola. Mine is Bob.
你确定不再待一会吗
Are you sure you don't want to stick around?
我很乐意帮助老年人
I enjoy helping elderly men
改善他们日渐衰老的身体
repair their aging bodies.
谢谢  家里还有事等着我做
Thanks, but I got a job I got to get back to,
蒂娜也得回去  另外我不怎么跳舞
and so does Tina, plus I don't really dance.
虽然巴西战舞涵盖一些舞蹈元素
Although Capoeira incorporates elements of dance,
但其实它是一种极其危险的武术
it is a highly dangerous form of martial arts.
对  你说得没错
Right. I'm sure it is.
它似乎是一种保持身材的好方法
It seems like a great way to stay in shape,
就像爵士健美操
like jazzercise.
这可不是爵士健美操
Not like jazzercise.
随便啦
Whatever you say.
同学们  你们想看看示范动作吗
Class, would you like to see a demonstration?
来  蒂娜  我们快走吧
Come on, Tina. Let's go right now.
好了  好了  我看到了  很可爱
Okay, okay. I saw your movie. It's very cute.
马尾鞭
Hyah! Ponytail!
你不能这样  你居然用头发打我的脸
Hey! You can't do that. You just hit me with your hair.
-马尾鞭  -快停下
- Ponytail! - Stop that!
老爸  我们走吧  快走
Dad, let's go. Come on.
等我一下
Give me a second here.
你是不是要开会了
What about your meeting?
已经开完了
I just had my meeting.
-开完了  -是的
- Right now? - Mm-hmm.
别  别
Don't. Don't.
我们该怎么办
What do we do?
-把那面旗扯下来给我  -老爸  不行
- Grab me that flag. - No, dad.
蒂娜  我们得从这里出去  是吧
Tina, we're gonna get out of there, all right?
让我想想  别出声
Just let me think. Shh!
好了  我有主意了
All right. I got an idea.
-你走到墙角那边然后大叫  -什么
- You go into the corner and yell. - What?
走到墙角那边  开始大喊大叫
Go in the corner and start yelling
假装你心脏病发作了  我借机跑出去
like you're having a heart attack, and I'll run out.
-好吧  -快去快去
- Okay. - Go. Go.
-好吧  -动作快  等等  回来
- Okay - Fast. Wait. Come back..
-我心脏病犯...  -别出声
- I'm having a heart... what? - Don't... shh!
别那么做  这主意傻透了
Don't do that. It's a dumb idea.
老爸  我好尴尬啊
Dad, I'm so embarrassed.
是吗
Oh, oh, are you?
真是抱歉  我一点也不觉得尴尬
I'm sorry because I'm not embarrassed at all
因为我刚拉了一裤子屎
because I just pooped my pants.
如果可以的话我每天都要这么做  蒂娜
I would do this every day if I could, Tina.
不不  他正在洗澡
No, no. He's in the shower now.
这样的事发生之后
Well, sometimes it's hard to feel clean
有时总觉得洗不干净
after something like that happens.
真是尴尬死了  好了  孩子们
It's very embarrassing. Okay, kids.
你们的父亲现在非常脆弱
Your father is very tender right now, all right?
不管干什么
Whatever you do,
都别提今天在蒂娜班上发生的事
do not mention what happened today at Tina's class.
表现得正常点
Just act normal.
你今天拉裤子啦
So you pooped your pants.
琳达  别提这茬
Linda, let's not talk about it.
这场打斗很不公平
Wasn't a fair fight.
他更年轻  又可爱又强壮
He's younger, and he's cute and strong.
琳达  这么说没用
Linda, this isn't helpful.
该你走的时候你就得走
Hey, when you got to go, you got to go.
琳达  别说了
Linda, stop!
你在和金泽打电话吗
Are you on the phone with Ginger?
没有  我得挂了
No. I got to go.
哈哈哈  抱歉  鲍鲍
Ha ha ha! Sorry, Bobby.
我不是嘲笑你
I'm not laughing at you.
我只是又想起了金泽那只死掉的猫
I was thinking about Ginger's dead cat again.
-老爸老爸老爸  -怎么了  露易丝
- Dad, dad, dad. - Yes, Louise?
-老爸老爸  -什么事
- Dad, dad, hi. - Yes? Hi.
你知不知道
Did you know that
要把一个人的鼻梁骨打进颅腔
it only takes two pounds of pressure
只需要两磅压力
to drive someone's nose bone into their brain?
那是...  啥
That's... what?
只要两磅压力  就这么简单  老爸
Two pounds. That's it, dad.
露易丝  你为什么要告诉我这个
Why are you telling me this, Louise?
我要复仇
Revenge.
复仇魂  复仇魂  复仇魂
Revengeourine, revengeourine, revengeourine.
-闭嘴  吉恩  -各位  听我说
- Cut it out, Gene. - All right. Listen, everybody.
今天发生的事情已经过去了
What happened today is in the past,
我们不要再讨论此事
and we're never gonna talk about it again ever.
我只是很高兴蒂娜就要退出训练班了
I'm just glad Tina is quitting the class,
是吧  蒂娜
right, Tina?
但是我的身体需要训练
But my body needs it.
你的身体需要和你父亲共同在餐馆工作
Your body needs to work in the restaurant with your father.
那好吧
Ohh... Oh, fine.
如果你需要我
If you need me,
我就躺在这里的地板上  等死
I'll be down here on the floor, dying.
好了  听起来不错  宝贝
All right. Sounds good, honey.
你得学学正确的呻吟方式  蒂娜
You have to learn to groan right, Tina.
-她的呻吟声很好听啊  -听起来怪怪的
- Hey, she groans fine. - It sounds weird.
既然你擅长呻吟  那你来呻吟一下
So you groan, then, if you're so good at it.
-这叫呻吟吗  -是啊
- That's a groan? - Yeah. Agh.
我来呻吟一下  让我呻吟一下
I'll do it. Let me do it.
蒂娜  够了  起来吧
Tina, enough already. Come on.
蒂娜  你男朋友来了
Tina, it's your boyfriend.
我的天
Oh, God.
-你好  -你来干嘛
- Ola. - What do you want?
我收到一条留言  上面说蒂娜心情低落
I got a message that Tina was very upset
她需要鼓励重返巴西战舞练功房
and needed to be encouraged to come back to the art of Capoeira.
一条留言  谁留的
A message? From who?
不用谢我  不用谢我
You're welcome, and... you're welcome.
很抱歉  蒂娜很忙  她正在烤肉
Well, I'm sorry. Tina is busy. She's working the grill.
没关系  我等着
It's okay. I'll wait.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我在找"鲜榨水果汁"
Well, I'm looking for your fresh-squeezed juice selection.
不在这张菜单上吗
Is it on another menu?
抱歉  在这里  给你
Oh. Sorry. Here. Yeah. Here it is.
这是同一张菜单
This is the same menu.
是啊  因为我们没有鲜榨水果汁
Yeah, because we don't have fresh-squeezed juice.
鲜榨水果汁真是二
Fresh-squeezed juice is stupid.
这可不是我的说话方式
That is not how I talk at all.
是  就是  巴西战舞也很二  好吧
Yes, it is. So is Capoeira. It's stupid, okay?
-老爸  别说了  -你好啊  蒂娜
- Dad, stop. - Oh, hello, Tina.
-我刚才没看到你  -没关系
- I didn't notice you. - That's okay.
你还好吗  蒂娜
Is everything all right with you, Tina?
我老爸不让我参加训练
My dad won't let me train anymore.
-蒂娜  -什么
- Tina... - What?
因为你把他踹出屎了
It's because you made him poop in his pants.
-天哪  -蒂娜
- Oh, my God. - Tina!
鲍勃  别这样  没什么好尴尬的
Bob, please. There is nothing to be embarrassed about.
受了伤的弱者被健壮的强者击败
It is quite common for a wounded animal
因而产生大肠运动
to make a bowel movement as he is defeated
这实在是一件平常不过的事
by a much stronger predator.
才不是因为你呢  因为当时是四点半
Hey, it wasn't you. It was 4:30.
来  鲍勃  我来给你示范几个
Here, Bob. Let me show you some very convenient
简便的括约肌紧缩练习
sphincter-tightening exercises.
-不用了  谢谢  -收紧  放松
- No, thank you. - Tight. Relax.
-我不想...  -收紧  放松
- I don't want... - Tight. Relax.
-快停下  -收紧
- Stop it! - Tight.
别在我的餐馆里做括约肌紧缩练习
Don't do sphincter-tightening exercises in my restaurant.
-那好吧  -谢了
- Okay. Fine. - Thank you.
我要在早上做这个练习
I'll be feeling this in the morning.
吉恩
Gene!
我的胃里现在充满了负面能量
Well, now my stomach is full of negative energy,
我已经没有胃口了  本来也没胃口
so I've lost my appetite, which is just as well.
我该去上课了
It's time for me to go to class.
蒂娜  你应该跟我一起去
Tina, you should come with me.
别忘了
Remember,
下周就要举行卓卡・德・考多艾斯晋级赛了
the Troca de Cordoes is next week.
卓卡・德・考多艾斯晋级赛
The Troca de Cordoes?
什么是卓卡・德・考多艾斯晋级赛
What's the Troca de Cordoes?
我感觉蒂娜要是好好练的话
I feel if Tina trains hard,
很有晋升黄带的潜力
she has the potential to receive a promotion to yellow cord.
蒂娜  听着  你哪儿都别想去
Tina, listen to me. You're not going anywhere.
-我是你老爸  -没错  蒂娜
- I'm your father. - Yes, Tina...
我可是你的巴西战舞老师
but I am your Capoeira instructor.
等一下  我要跟你去上课
Wait. I'm going to class with you.
蒂娜  你这是做什么
Tina, what are you doing?
老爸  你不懂的
Dad, you don't understand.
我懂的是你被禁足了  即刻生效
I understand you're grounded, effective right now.
-鲍勃  让她去吧  -不行
- Bob, let her go. - No.
她被禁足了  琳
She's grounded, Lin.
我们只是需要时间冷静一下
We all just need a minute to calm down.
蒂娜  你一旦走出那个门
Hey, Tina, you walk out that door,
就别想再当我的烤肉师了
and you're no longer my grill cook.
老爸  冷静  我去把她叫回来
Dad. Calm down. I'll go get her.
你赶紧给我从这儿滚出去  听见没
You get out of here! You hear me?
永远别回头  对我们来说你已经死了
Never look back! You are dead to us.
抱歉  老爸  我也爱莫能助
Sorry, dad. There's no getting through to that one.
谢了  露易丝  你真是帮了大忙
Thanks, Louise. That was very helpful.
今天是个很重要的日子呢
Big day.
非常  非常重要
Big, big day.
今天要举行卓卡・德・考多艾斯晋级赛
The Troca de Cordoes.
我知道
I know.
我知道今天举行卓卡・德・考多艾斯晋级赛
I know it's the Troca de Cordoes.
-跟你说了我不去  -好吧  随便你
- I told you, I'm not going. - Okay. Fine.
我再说最后一次
I'm just gonna say one more time,
我认为你应该去给你女儿打气
I think that you should come support your daughter.
琳达  她刚才被我禁足了
Linda, I just grounded her.
是你让她走的
You let her go.
鲍勃  对不起  行了吧  走嘛
Bob, I'm sorry. Okay. Come on.
这只是个必经阶段罢了
It's just a phase.
我知道你是怕失去你的宝贝女儿
I know you're afraid you're gonna lose your little girl.
很温馨  但你是怎么想的
That's sweet, but what'd you think,
难道她一辈子
she's gonna spend the rest of her life
都得在你身边帮你烤肉吗
standing next to you grilling burgers?
蠢死了  什么一辈子
That's silly, spending the rest of her life
在我身边帮我烤肉
standing next to me grilling burgers.
当然不是
Of course not.
虽然也没什么不对
I mean, nothing wrong with it.
我是说  应该挺有趣的
I mean, it would be fun.
蒂娜魂  蒂娜魂  蒂娜魂
Tinarine, Tinarine, cha cha cha, Tinarine!
蒂娜  蒂娜  蒂娜  蒂娜  蒂娜魂
Tina, Tina, Tina, Tina, Tinarine!
-我们准备好了  -好棒
- We're ready. - Okay.
我来了
I'm coming.
抱歉  蒂娜  我是不会去的
I'm sorry, Tina. I'm not going.
我爱这家店
I love this restaurant.
你不能因为性感战舞课
You can't abandon the things you love
就抛弃你的挚爱
just because of sexy dance fighting.
如果我是汉堡  你就会来看了吧
If I were a hamburger, you'd come watch me fight.
干得好  鲍勃
Good job, Bob.
吉恩  露易丝  我们走
Gene, Louise, come on.
我们要去参加蒂娜的空手道绶带大会了
We're going to Tina's karate concert.
这么说你今天不去报仇喽
So you're not going to get revenge today?
不  露易丝  我不去
No, Louise. I'm not.
好  我知道了
Okay. Got it.
那我就不带你的信用卡去了
Then I won't bring your credit card,
它被我做成了忍者飞镖
which I cut into a ninja star.
你把我的信用卡给剪了
Oh, you cut my credit card?
做成了忍者飞镖
Into a ninja star.
铃鼓魂  铃鼓魂
Tambourine, tambourine,
忍者镖  信用卡  铃鼓魂
ninja star, credit card, tambourine.
汉堡店上演家庭闹剧了  是吧
Family drama at Bob's Burgers, huh?
鲍勃  鲍勃  鲍鲍
Bob. Bob. Bobby.
怎么了  泰迪
What, Teddy?
卓卡・德・考多艾斯是什么玩意儿
What's a Troca de Cordoes?
是一种仪式  像毕业典礼一样
It's a ceremony. It's like a graduation.
但那家伙是个变态
Yeah, but this guy is a creep,
我得坚持我的立场
and I got to stand my ground.
她在一段时间内要对这家店负责的
She made a commitment to this restaurant, period.
-"交换绳带"  -什么
- "Exchange of strands." - What?
我刚查了下卓卡・德・考多艾斯
I just looked up Troca de Cordoes.
在葡萄牙语里是"交换绳带"的意思
It's Portuguese for "Exchange of strands."
听起来很重要啊
Sounds momentous.
就在今天  交换绳带
This very day, she's becoming a woman,
她就要蜕变成女人了
exchanging her strands.
什么  是那么说的吗
Wait. That's what it says?
对  就是这么说的
Yeah. That's what it says.
上面说她就要蜕变成女人了
It says she's becoming a woman?
对啊  你自己看
Well, yeah. Take a look.
你要怎么办  鲍勃
What you gonna do about it, Bob?
这上并没说会变成女人
Doesn't say becoming a woman.
不  往下读
No. Read into it.
这上面说  "交换绳带"
It says, "Exchange of strands."
就是交换绳带
It's exchanging strands.
根本没说要变成女人什么的
Has nothing about her becoming a woman.
你在说什么  鲍勃
What are you saying, Bob?
你又在说什么  泰迪
What are you saying, Teddy?
我只想说  要是我的女儿要变成女人了
Just, if my daughter was becoming a woman,
我会在她身边支持她的
I would want to be there.
她并没有要变成女人  泰迪
She's not becoming a woman, Teddy.
我是说  如果她要变的话
No, but if she was, I'm saying.
她又不是我女儿
She's not my daughter.
你刚刚又说了一遍
You were the one who just said it again.
滚出去  出去  泰迪
Get out. Get out, Teddy.
-我要买单  -从我的店里滚出去
- I want to pay my bill! - Get out of my restaurant!
我要买单
I want to pay my bill.
你的账单  四块一毛六  你个变态
There's your bill... $4.16, pervert.
-四块  变态  变态  -变态
- $4... Pervert? Pervert? - Pervert.
-你骂谁变态  -账单上就那么写的
- Who you calling pervert? - It's written on the bill.
给你四块一毛六  鲍勃  吃屎去吧
Here's your $4.16, Bob. Best of luck.
世界上餐馆多的是
There's a million restaurants I can go to.
那就去个遍吧  泰迪
Then go to them all, Teddy!
-对不起  泰迪  我失控了  -不
- I'm sorry, Teddy. I get carried away. - No.
是我走火入魔了  对不起
I blew my stack. I'm sorry.
我只是不能接受  她这么快就长大了
It's just, she's growing up so fast.
还有  我昨天又拉裤子了
Also, I crapped my pants yesterday.
我知道  听说了
Yeah. I know. I heard. Ha ha!
我要关门了
Listen. I got to close up shop.
我得去个地方
I have somewhere to be.
所以你们真得走了
So you really do have to get out.
巴西魂
Brazil.
乖儿子好样的
That's my son.
天啊
Oh, God.
巴西魂
Brazil! Sha!
燃烧吧巴西魂  结束了
And I'm a... Brazil. Finished.
祝贺你  尼尔
Congratulations, Neil.
恭喜你获得黄带
You have earned your yellow cord.
蒂娜  到你了
Tina, you're next.
太好了  加油  蒂娜  你是最棒的
All right! Go, Tina! You're doing great.
鲍鲍  你能来可真好
So glad you came, Bobby.
她看起来很享受嘛
She looks like she's having a good time.
燃烧吧巴西魂
Hyah! Brazil!
感谢参与  测试结束
Thank you. The test is complete.
很遗憾  蒂娜  你没有通过
I'm sorry, Tina, but you have failed.
请坐吧
Have a seat.
下一个接受黄带测试的是嘉内尔
The next student testing for her yellow corda is Janelle.
怎么回事  给我等一下
Hey, hey, hey, hey, wait, wait. Wait a minute. Wait.
请不要扰乱我们的绶带仪式  鲍勃
Please do not interrupt the ceremony, Bob.
快把那根破带子给我女儿系上
Just give her the stupid cord.
难道你看不出来这对她有多重要吗
Can't you see how much this means to her?
很抱歉  鲍勃
I'm sorry, Bob,
她没做那五个基本动作
but she did not perform the five elementary motions,
所以不能授予她黄带
so she will not be receiving her yellow corda.
你说什么  她表现得比尼尔好多了
What? She did better than Neil.
那傻小子刚才只是瞎比划一气
That kid was a mess out there.
-什么  -少胡说
- What? - Hey!
你们自己也心知肚明
Oh, you know it's true.
我认为蒂娜做了全部五个傻缺的基本动作
Tina did all five of the elementary weird motions, I think.
那个她做了  那个她做了很多次
She did that one. She did that one a lot.
你在这指手画脚的
Is this because
是因为那天我把你踹拉稀了吧
I made you poop your pantalones?
我不是来维护我自己的
This isn't about me.
我是来维护蒂娜的
It's about Tina.
真的吗
Oh, is that what you think?
好了  不跟你废话了  我要拿根带子
All right. That's it. I'm taking a corda.
别碰
Don't touch.
-马尾鞭  -别闹了
- Ponytail! - Stop that.
来试试啊
Make me.
打  打  打  打  打
Fight, fight, fight, fight, fight!
鼻梁骨
Nose bone!
把他的鼻梁骨砸进他那猪头里
Nose bone into the brain
把他的皮剥了穿在身上
and skin him and wear him like a costume.
好了  露易丝  好了
All right, Louise. All right.
成  开打吧
All right. Here we go.
鲍鲍  别跟他打
Bobby, don't do this.
我得力挺蒂娜
I have to stand up for Tina.
可是  鲍勃  看看现在几点了
But, Bob, look at the clock.
-都4:28了  -我知道  琳
- It's 4:28. - I know, Lin.
我清楚得很  要是拉肚子就让它拉吧
I know, and if I poop, I poop.
鲍鲍
Oh, Bobby...
杰罗  杰罗  杰罗  杰罗  杰罗
Jairo, Jairo, Jairo, Jairo, Jairo...
等一下
Heh heh heh. Hold on.
我刚才还没准备好呢...
I wasn't ready that time, so...
巴西魂  马尾鞭
Brazil! Ponytail!
收紧你的括约肌  鲍鲍
Keep your sphincter tight, Bobby.
我没事  琳
I'm okay, Lin.
-老爸  用这个  -露易丝
- Use this, dad. - Ow! Louise...
马尾鞭
Ponytail!
巴西魂
Brazil!
还没尝够苦头吗
Hey, you want some more?
让他别打了  妈妈
Make him stop, mom.
巴西魂
Brazil!
老爸说得对
Dad was right.
杰罗就是个混蛋
Jairo is just a jerk...
一个性感的  世俗的
A sexy, sensual,
变态的  性感的混蛋
creepy, sexy jerk.
上啊  老爸  加油
Go, dad! Come on.
老爸  老爸
Dad, dad...
老爸  老爸  老爸  老爸  老爸
Dad, dad, dad, dad, dad, dad, dad, dad, dad, dad, dad...
谢了  蒂娜
Thanks, Tina.
我想在哪撂倒他  他就在哪倒
I got him right where I want him.
够了
Enough.
-制服不错嘛  -谢谢
- Hey, nice form. - Thanks.
我很抱歉  杰罗在大家面前
Sorry Jairo knocked you down
撂倒你25到30次
25 to 30 times in front of everyone.
是啊  很抱歉没能拿到属于你的黄带
Yeah. Sorry I couldn't get your yellow corda.
没事啦  谢谢你为我挨顿揍
It's okay. Thanks for getting beat up for me.
话说回来
Anyway,
我现在对俄罗斯的壶球力量训练有点兴趣
I'm kind of interested in Russian kettleball strength training now.
别给我看这个  因为我...
Don't make me watch this because I...
-我去给老妈看  -好
- I'll show mom. - Yeah.
给你一个惊喜
Well, I have a surprise for you.
-你晋升了  -真的吗
- You got a promotion. - Really?
-是升职了吗  -不是
- I get a raise? - No...
你获得的是一双黄色清洁手套
But you get these yellow dish gloves.
我将这双黄手套  颁发给你
I present to you your yellow gloves.
真有意思  我们快走吧
So much fun. Well, we better get going.
好
Yeah.
码头边的那只死海豹可不会自己捅自己哦
That dead seal down at the pier isn't gonna poke itself.
等等  等一下  你们两个今天得干活
Wait, wait. Hold on. You two are working today.
什么  我们两个今天可不当班
What? We're not on the schedule today.
看  看看你自己写的值班表
Read. Learn how to read the schedule that you write.
亲爱的蒂娜宝贝  我们今天给你放一天假
Tina, honey, we're giving you the day off.
去玩吧
Go do something fun.
死海豹在哪呢  怎么一回事
Do you know where this dead seal is? What's that about?
是一只死海豹  妈妈
It's a dead seal, mom. It's...
一只被冲上来的死海豹
A washed-up seal.
他们去捅那只海豹去了
They go poke at it.
我们还要抽它
And we're gonna slap it.
发出的声音很好听
It makes a great sound.
我将拍打声取样了  听起来很淫荡
Then I sample the slaps. Sounds like an orgy.
我喜欢死海豹
I like dead seals,
但我还是留在这里吧
but I think I'm gonna stay here instead.
其实我今天干活干得很高兴
I'm actually having fun at work today.
还有  我想享受一下父女互动时间
Besides, it's our father-daughter time.
-你丫的  -吉恩  我们快跑
- Sucker! - Gene, run.
跑  跑  跑  跑  跑到海豹那里
Run, run, run, run, run to the seal!